# Wai Lok Cheng

wailokcheng020@gmail.com

**Location** London, United Kingdom **Website** lok020.github.io/portfolio/

Visa Status UK Right to work LinkedIn linkedin.com/in/lok020/

Nationality British National (Overseas)
Github github.com/lok020/

Front-end developer with over 3 years of experience working with JavaScript, HTML/CSS, and React. Possess the ability to collaborate with other developers, construct solutions, and deliver effectively. My greatest strength is curiosity, which enables me to keep passionate about the world of new technology. Obtained Bachelor of Science in Computer Science degree in 2017.

# **Experience**

## **Zetakey Solutions Limited - Web Application Developer**

August 2018 - March 2022

Zetakey is an embedded software company. Founded with a group of embedded software experts with vast experience in embedded, open-source software. In recent years it has expanded into the IoT field and stepped foot in the web application territory.

- Leading a team of 3 for over 1 year with front-end UI/UX design and development under a modularized approach, designing data structure, coding & problem solving, and code testing. My role mainly focuses on front-end UI/UX design and development.
- Collaboration tools used include Git, Fork, Google Drive, Google Docs, Zoom, and Teamviewer.
- Creating websites according to customers' needs by using JavaScript, HTML/CSS, and React.
- Designed dynamic and cross-browser compatible websites based on functionality, accessibility, and aesthetics.
- Clients include companies from the medical, elevators, optical fiber industries.
- The medical project's objective was to provide hospital staff with informational management, and assistance on the operational procedures. The web app is separated into 3 sections; operative, administration, and configuration.
  - The operative section gathers stored data from the database and live data from medical devices to display them as informational graphs and tables. Another purpose is to record situational information into an e-form.
  - The administration section provides management for patients, cases, nurses, doctors, and anesthetists.
  - The configuration section allows users to set up the e-form, the web app color mode, medical devices, etc.
  - The project used socket IO to receive live data, and then used API and query to fetch information from the database. Finally utilized react, HTML, CSS, and javascript to create a web app for control and display purposes.
- The elevator project's objective was to allow users to configure profiles and call elevators in different ways.
  - The setup process includes filling up a form with personal information, registering a personal picture through a personal device, and gathering consent from the user. Then all information will be stored in the database with an encryption mechanism.
  - The project used different innovative technologies including facial recognition, QR reading, palm vein scanning, Kiosk, etc.
- The optical fiber project's objective was to display maps of where the company lay its optical fiber, and display instant status for each section.
  - The web app uses the coordinates of the optical fibers and traces them onto a map. Then matches the status information from the database for each section.
  - o Zoom in and zoom out of the map triggers re-render status size, and align the icon and information.

## **Splendor Design & Construction Limited - Web Developer**

June 2016 - August 2016

Splendor is a one-step interior design and construction company. Provided designs tailored to clients' needed and created their dream home with excellent quality.

- The main task was to create a website for Splendor containing pictures, projects, and information as a showcase.
- Designed dynamic and cross-browser compatible pages using JavaScript, and HTML/CSS.
- Used responsive web design with CSS media queries to deliver an excellent user experience.

#### **Education**

## **Bachelor of Science in Computer Science**

August 2013 - December 2017

Washington State University, School of Electrical Engineering and Computer Science

### **Associate in Arts and Sciences**

March 2013

**Everett Community College** 

#### Skills

- Web development
- UI/UX
- JavaScript
- HTML/CSS
- Node.js
- GIT

## Languages

- English (Fluent)
- Cantonese (Native)
- Mandarin (Fluent)